Inventory of the George F. Koether papers
Hoover Institution Archives
George F. Koether papers
1829-2003
1943-1987
88021
Hoover Institution Archives
21 manuscript boxes (8.7 linear feet)
Correspondence, speeches and writings, reports, pamphlets, clippings, photographs, and printed matter relating to laissez-faire economic and political thought, monetary policy, and economic conditions in the United States.
Koether, George F., 1907-2006
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1988.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
George Koether was a journalist, speechwriter, businessman, lecturer, economist, a friend to Ludwig and Margit von Mises, and a longtime ambassador for Misesian economics. He was born on July 28, 1907, in Newark, New Jersey. He grew up in Detroit, Michigan, and attended Albion College in Michigan, where he studied journalism. He also studied business administration at Columbia University, New York.
In 1930, Koether married Viola B. Kennedy and began his journalism career, as a copy editor for Look Magazine in 1943 and later serving as the automotive and transportation editor in 1952. Koether was a three-time awardee of the Ted V. Rodgers Journalism Award for outstanding articles and editorials on highway improvement and use, and contributed articles about the automotive industry for the World Book Encyclopedia. Koether also wrote for the The Saturday Evening Post, Architectural Forum, and Christian Economics, on many topics ranging from currency and inflation to politics and economics. In the 1940s and 1950s, Koether began correspondence with Henry L. Hazlitt, editor of, The Freeman, who encouraged Koether to write for the publication.
In 1958, Koether worked as a public relations official for the United States Steel Corporation in New York, and he was a member of the Public Relations Society of America in the 1960s. He also served on the staff of organizations such as the Foundation for Economic Education (FEE) and the Christian Freedom Foundation.
Koether also served as lecturer for the University of Michigan, the New York Civic Education Forum, and the Ludwig von Mises Institute at Auburn College, Alabama.
In the 1970s, Koether served as chairman for the Committee for Monetary Research and Education, Inc. Around 1976, Koether produced a series of audio-visual films on free market economics and monetary policy. While working for Ingersoll-Rand Corporation, Koether wrote a series of educational materials for employees on economics. Similar curricula was developed and targeted for the layperson at other corporations and schools.
During the 1980s and throughout his retirement, Koether was a benefactor to the Ludwig von Mises Institute at Auburn College. He passed away March 22, 2006.
Scope and Content of Collection
The majority of the collection is composed of Subject Files, which contain correspondence, speeches, writings, reports, studies, pamphlets, clippings, and other printed matter on communism, education, religion, politics, economy, economists, and geographic areas. The Correspondence series contains letters, memoranda, and printed matter relating to Koether's interest in economic and political policy, corporate industries, and political societies. Also included is a section of Writings, which contains drafts, notes, books, and published articles.
Arrangement Statement
The collection maintains the original arrangement and hierarchical order of the George F. Koether when possible.
Related Collections
William Warren Bartley miscellaneous papers, Hoover Institution Archives
Center for Libertarian Studies records, Hoover Institution Archives
Richard C. Cornuelle papers, Hoover Institution Archives
John Davenport papers, Hoover Institution Archives
John Exter speeches and writings, Hoover Institution Archives
Gottfried Haberler papers, Hoover Institution Archives
Friedrich A. von Hayek papers, Hoover Institution Archives
Mont Pèlerin Society records, Hoover Institution Archives
Dieter Spethmann papers, Hoover Institution Archives
Mont Pèlerin Society.; Automobile industry and trade--United States.; Economics.; Economists--Austrian school.; Economists.; Finance, Personal.; Inflation--Finance.; Journalists.; Laissez-faire.; Liberty.; Look magazine.; Monetary policy.; Money--Pictorial works.; Switzerland--Mont Pèlerin Society.; Traffic safety--United States.; Transportation, Automotive--United States.; United States--Economic conditions--1945-
- Subject File, 1829-1989
  - African nations, pamphlets and printed matter, 1951-1985 (Box-folder 1: 1)
    Scope and Contents note
    Topics include the Republic of the Congo relations with United Nations forces and apartheid in South Africa.
  - Agriculture, 1887-1987 (Box-folder 1: 2)
    Includes a typescript speech by United States President Grover Cleveland on February 16, 1887, to the House of Representatives regarding House Bill 10203.
  - American Affairs: A Quarterly Journal of Free Opinion, 1949, January-October (Box-folder 1: 3)
  - Anti-trust, 1957-1967 (Box-folder 1: 4)
  - Banking, circa 1915-1988
    - Deregulation, 1958-1988 (Box-folder 1: 5)
    - International Monetary Fund (IMF), circa 1915-1974 (Box-folder 1: 6)
    - Printed matter, 1945-1988 (Box-folder 1: 7)
  - Baruch, Bernard M. (economist), 1950-1952 (Box-folder 1: 8)
  - Blanshard, Paul (socialist), 1928-1951 (Box-folder 1: 9)
  - Bolivia, 1956-1957 (Box-folder 1: 10)
  - Bonds (savings), 1948-1951 (Box-folder 1: 11)
  - Bowles, Chester (Governor's biography), 1949-1951 (Box-folder 1: 12)
  - Bradley, Omar N., 1949-1951 (Box-folder 1: 13)
  - Brannan, Charles Franklin (United States Secretary of Agriculture) speeches, 1949-1952 (Box-folder 1: 14)
  - Browder, Earl, 1951 (Box-folder 1: 15)
  - Business, 1970 (Box-folder 1: 16)
  - Capital (investments and spending), 1949-1986 (Box-folder 2: 1)
  - Capital formation, 1947-1981 (Box-folder 2: 2)
  - Capitalism, 1960-1986 (Box-folder 2: 3)
    Includes Corporate Responsibility: The Viability of Capitalism in an Era of Militant Demands, 1960, "Affirmative Action: A Praiseworthy Intention, A Corruptive Technique," (Howard) and, "Business and the Gay Liberation Movement" (Shenfield).
  - United States Central Intelligence Agency (CIA), circa 1945-1953 (Box-folder 2: 4)
  - Classical references and excerpts, circa 1949-1980 (Box-folder 2: 5)
  - Committee for Economic Development (CED), 1937-1966 (Box-folder 2: 6-8)
    Includes clippings and other printed matter, drafts, and correspondence.
  - Commodity Credit Corporation, 1950-1951 (Box-folder 2: 9)
  - Common market, 1958-1981 (Box-folder 2: 10)
  - Communism, 1948-1985
    - Cripps, Sir Richard Stafford, 1949-1985 (Box-folder 2: 11)
    - Field, Frederick Vanderbilt, 1948-1951 (Box-folder 2: 12)
    - Jessup, Philip, 1949-1951 (Box-folder 2: 13)
    - McCarthy, Joseph R. and McCarthyism, 1949-1953 (Box-folder 3: 1)
  - Communism in the United States of America, 1943-1961
    - Clippings, 1950-1951 (Box-folder 3: 2)
    - Education, 1943-1952 (Box-folder 3: 3)
    - Government, 1949-1951 (Box-folder 3: 4)
    - Labor and unions, 1950-1969 (Box-folder 3: 5)
    - Pamphlets and other materials, 1947-1952 (Box-folder 3: 6)
  - Competition, 1974-1980 (Box-folder 3: 7)
    Includes Mont Pelerin Society 1980 general meeting report and a monetary policy panel discussion outline entitled, "Monopoly or Competition Policy?".
  - Congress (United States) and Reagan administration clippings, 1978-1987 (Box-folder 3: 8)
  - Connecticut Taxpayers' Association, perodicals, 1974-1983 (Box-folder 3: 9)
  - Conspiracy, 1920-1987 (Box-folder 3: 10)
    Includes Citizens for Foreign Aid Reform's (C-FAR) Canadian Issues Series and a typescript speech "The Communist Takeover of America," by Howard E. Kershner.
  - The Constitution (United States), 1949-1979 (Box-folder 3: 11)
    Includes two issues of Dollars & Sense on the matter of Congress and the Senate Subcommittee on the Constitution to send constitutional amendment to require a balanced federal budget (July and September 1979).
  - Consumerism--consumer bills article, 1975 (Box-folder 3: 12)
  - Council of Economic Advisers (CEA), 1962 (Box-folder 3: 13)
  - Credit--consumer credit and public debt, 1940-1958 (Box-folder 3: 14)
    Includes "College on Credit," by United Student Aid Funds, Inc. and printed matter on bank credit and credit policies.
  - Debt, 1956-1987
    Includes reprint of "The Growth of Debt and Money in the United States, 1800-1950: A Suggested Interpretation," by John G. Gurley and E. S. Shaw of the Brookings Institution, 1957.
    - Deficit spending and Federal debt limits, 1962-1987 (Box-folder 3: 15)
    - Government and personal, 1957-1983 (Box-folder 3: 16)
  - Democracy, 1959-1961 (Box-folder 3: 17)
  - Depreciation, 1956-1970 (Box-folder 3: 18)
    Includes some materials from the American Economic Foundation and the United States steel industry.
  - Ecology--economic perspectives, 1978-1980 (Box-folder 4: 1)
  - Economics (Box-folder 4: 2-3)
    Arrangement Statement
    Clippings and files labeled by the creator as "Cockeyed Economics" and "Economic Stupidities," under the Economics file. Covers topics such as inflation, welfare, Dag Hammarskjöld (2nd Secretary-General of the United Nations), Robert L. Heilbroner (economist), and taxation.
  - Economic theory, 1910-1984
    - Austrian economics, 1910-1981 (Box-folder 4: 4)
    - American School of Economics pamphlets, no date (Box-folder 4: 5)
    - Economic thought, 1931-1981 (Box-folder 4: 6)
    - Keynesianism, 1945-1977 (Box-folder 4: 7)
    - Printed matter, 1935-1984 (Box-folder 4: 8)
  - Economists, 1952-1986
    - 1952-1982 (Box-folder 5: 1)
    - 1955-1980 (Box-folder 5: 2)
    - 1958-1986 (Box-folder 5: 3)
    - Austrian school, 1960-1984 (Box-folder 5: 4)
    - Burns, Arthur F., 1954-1962 (Box-folder 5: 5)
    - Hazlitt, Henry, 1959-1981 (Box-folder 5: 6)
  - Education, 1936-1982
    Pamphlets, clippings, and other printed matter covering topics such as economic implications in eduction, the National Education Association (NEA), and public schools.
    - NEA pamphlets, 1936-1980 (Box-folder 6: 1)
    - Economic implications, 1975-1982 (Box-folder 6: 2)
    - Schools, 1979-1981 (Box-folder 6: 3)
    - Pamphlets, 1954-1982 (Box-folder 6: 4)
  - Einstein, Albert, 1950-1953 (Box-folder 6: 5)
  - Employment, 1960-1978 (Box-folder 6: 6)
  - Environmentalists, 1979 (Box-folder 6: 7)
  - Eurodollars, 1975-1982 (Box-folder 6: 8)
    Regarding the United States dollar versus the Eurodollar and conference paper, "Eurodollars Explained: A Pedagogic Note," by Gunter Duffey, Harriman, New York, 1979.
  - Exchange controls, 1965-1987
    Includes the works of Hans F. Sennholz, Wilhem Röpke, and Mont Pelerin Society conference papers. Also includes pamphlets, newspaper clippings of foreign exchange rates, and articles on currency exchange rates, coinage, and monetary exchange.
    - Articles and reports, 1968-1986 (Box-folder 6: 9)
    - Foreign currency, 1965-1987 (Box-folder 6: 10)
    - Coinage, 1974-1976 (Box-folder 6: 11)
  - Federal Reserve System (United States), 1949-1989 (Box-folder 7: 1-4)
    Includes articles, printed matter, and monetary policy reports.
  - Finletter, Thomas K. (United States Air Force Secretary), 1950-1951 (Box-folder 7: 5)
  - Gold standard, 1940-1984 (Box-folder 7: 6)
  - Gold and silver value, 1976-1982 (Box-folder 7: 7)
  - Government (United States) (Box-folder 8: 1-5)
    Includes materials on the Internal Revenue Service (IRS), the United States Postal Service, regulations, bureaucracy, and presidental power.
  - Gross National Product (GNP), 1987 (Box-folder 8: 6)
  - Growth (economic), 1959-1981 (Box-folder 8: 7-8)
  - The Heller Report: "Fiscal Problems of Germany,", 1950-1961 (Box-folder 8: 9)
    Includes "Fiscal Problems of Germany," by the ECA (United States, Economic Corporation Administration) Team on Fiscal Problems of Germany (West), of which Walter W. Heller joined the last weeks of the team visit to the Federal Republic of Germany. Co-authors: Alvin H. Hansen and Richard A. Musgrave.
  - History, 1896-1972 (Box-folder 8: 10)
  - Income and income taxes, 1938-1982 (Box-folder 8: 11)
  - Industrial production, 1829-1980 (Box-folder 8: 12)
  - Inflation, circa 1934-1989
    Arrangement follows creator's original order, and materials include transcriptions, writings, and pamphlets. Includes the reprint, "Du Pont de Nemours on the Dangers of Inflation," by Pierre Samuel du Pont, translated by Edmond E. Lincoln, Baker Library, Harvard Graduate School of Business Administratrion (1950), as well as a chronology of inflation during the French Revolution. Materials also cover the causes and effects of inflation in the United States and post-World War II German experiences with inflation. Works by Henry Hazlitt, Dr. Hans F. Sennholz, copies of correspondence from Murray N. Rothbard, and a typescript copy of "The German Experiences With Inflation," by Ludwig Rosenberg are also inlcuded
    - 1948-1958 (Box-folder 9: 1)
    - 1950-1983 (Box-folder 9: 2)
    - 1952-1989 (Box-folder 9: 3)
    - Causes, circa 1934-1979 (Box-folder 9: 4)
    - Foreign and domestic, 1950-1981 (Box-folder 9: 5)
    - Printed matter, 1952-1980 (Box-folder 9: 6)
  - Interest rates, 1957-1981 (Box-folder 10: 1)
  - Internal Revenue Service (IRS), United States Department of the Treasury, 1975-1986 (Box-folder 10: 2)
  - Intervention, 1949-1986 (Box-folder 10: 3)
  - Kellems, Vivien--taxes, 1949-1952 (Box-folder 10: 4)
  - Kennan, George F., United States Ambassador to Russia, 1950-1952 (Box-folder 10: 5)
  - Labor, 1934-1981 (Box-folder 10: 6-8)
    Includes The Heritage Foundation Policy Studies work "The International Labor Organization: Miroring the U.N.'s problems," by Walter Galenson, and related material on coercion and featherbedding.
  - Labor law, 1949-1980 (Box-folder 10: 9)
  - Labor monopoly, 1949-1961 (Box-folder 10: 10)
  - Labor unions, 1937-1977 (Box-folder 10: 11-12)
  - Labor union power, 1944-1986 (Box-folder 11: 1)
  - Law, 1957-1987 (Box-folder 11: 2)
    Includes an excerpt from Bruno Leoni's "Freedom and the Law" and Frederich A. Hayek's Law, Legislation and Liberty "The Miscarriage of the Democratic Ideal: A Recapitualation," 1973.
  - Manufacturing, 1974 (Box-folder 11: 3)
  - The media (television), 1977-1980 (Box-folder 11: 4)
  - Medicine--health, 1977-1981 (Box-folder 11: 5)
  - Mexican oil, clippings, 1958 (Box-folder 11: 6)
  - Monetary policy, 1864-1986 (Box-folder 11: 7-8)
    Includes photocopy of "La Question des Banques," by M.L. Wolowski, 1864. In French.
    - Articles and reports, 1864-1985
    - Clippings, 1952-1986
  - Money supply, 1949-1981 (Box-folder 11: 9)
  - Natural law, 1981 March (Box-folder 11: 10)
  - Planning--economic, 1975 (Box-folder 12: 1)
  - Politics, 1980, undated (Box-folder 12: 2)
  - Press (newspaper journalism), 1960-1987 (Box-folder 12: 3)
  - Price controls, 1950-1982 (Box-folder 12: 4)
  - Pricing, 1956-1981 (Box-folder 12: 5)
  - Productivity, 1976-1982 (Box-folder 12: 6)
  - Profits, 1941-1979 (Box-folder 12: 7-9)
    Includes drafts, articles, typescripts, and printed matter on profits and their effects on taxes and prices.
  - Rand, Ayn--critiques, 1965-1984 (Box-folder 12: 10)
  - Religion, circa 1958-1985 (Box-folder 12: 11)
  - Rhodesia, 1978 (Box-folder 12: 12)
  - Ruether, Walter Philip, 1948-1969 (Box-folder 21: 3)
    Biographical materials, writings about and by Reuther, and printed matter in the creator's original order.
  - Savings, 1944-1956 (Box-folder 12: 13)
  - Science, 1951-1985 (Box-folder 12: 14)
  - Socialism, 1904-1982 (Box-folder 13: 1)
  - Social Security reform, 1950-1985 (Box-folder 13: 2)
    Includes printed matter:
    The Bureau of National Affairs, Inc. (1950). Expanded Social Security: An Editorial Summary and Subject-by-Subject Analysis of the Social Security Act of 1950 with Text of Statute. Washington, DC: The Bureau of National Affairs, Inc.
    Ferrara, Peter J. "Social Security Reform: The Family Plan." (1982). Critical Issues [series]. Washington, DC: The Heritage Foundation.
  - Sociology, undated (Box-folder 13: 3)
  - Statistics, 1955-1982 (Box-folder 13: 4)
    Includes a subfolder entitled "Steel Statistics," along with clippings and the journal article "By the Numbers," by Thomas Sowell Policy Review, Winter 1982, pp. 9-27.
  - Subsidies, 1960 (Box-folder 13: 5)
  - Tariffs, 1977-1980 (Box-folder 13: 6)
  - Taxes, 1950-1982 (Box-folder 13: 7)
  - Taxation, 1958-1989 (Box-folder 13: 8)
  - U.S.S.R. (Union of Soviet Socialist Republics), 1961-1986 (Box-folder 13: 9)
  - Unions, 1972-1977 (Box-folder 13: 10)
  - United Nations, circa 1979-1983 (Box-folder 13: 11)
  - Videotape cassette recorder (VCR) techonology, 1978-1979 (Box-folder 13: 12)
  - Wage rates--minimum wage, 1948-1978 (Box-folder 13: 13)
    Includes articles by economist and professor Walter E. Williams.
  - Welfare, 1976-1987 (Box-folder 13: 14)
  - Wheat, 1973 (Box-folder 13: 15)
    Contains:
    Rueters, "U.S. Offers Soviet More Subsidized Wheat," [article]. The Globe and Mail, Saturday, November 28, 1987.
    Luttrell, Clifton B. "The Russian Wheat Deal--Hindsight vs. Foresight," [reprint], 1973. Orginally published October, 1973 by the Federal Reserve Bank of St. Louis.
  - World government, 1946-1982 (Box-folder 13: 16)
    Includes articles about the World Bank and of The World Bank Group.
- Correspondence, 1928-1988
  Includes correspondence between Koether and fellow economists and organizations, covering topics such as the steel industry and industial policies, Koether's publishing activities, monetary policy, and political societies. Correspondence files are arranged according to the creator's file system where possible and do not follow conventional alphabetical order. Some files may contain correspondence about an individual, as well as with them.
  - A, 1952-1984 (Box-folder 14: 1)
  - American Coalition, 1942-1951 (Box-folder 14: 2)
  - Atlas Economic Research Foundation, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 14: 3)
  - Audouin, Raol, 1977-1984 (Box-folder 14: 4)
  - Ayau, Manuel F., 1975-1984 (Box-folder 14: 5)
  - Buckley, William F., Jr., 1951 (Box-folder 14: 6)
  - C, 1949-1978 (Box-folder 14: 7)
  - Christian Freedom Foundation, 1950-1952 (Box-folder 14: 8)
  - Church League of America, 1981 (Box-folder 14: 9)
  - Committee for Monetary Research and Education (CMRE), 1975-1982 (Box-folder 14: 10-11)
  - Cornuelle, Herbert C., 1949-1959 (Box-folder 14: 12)
  - Cornuelle, Richard C., 1956-1958 (Box-folder 14: 13)
  - D, 1951-1983 (Box-folder 14: 14)
    Includes some correspondence about Spiritual Mobilization.
  - De Mille Foundation, 1949-1979 (Box-folder 14: 15)
    Includes some correspondence between Cecil B. De Mille and Herbert Cournelle.
  - Du Pont (E.I. Du Pont de Nemours & Company), 1957 (Box-folder 14: 16)
  - Dykes, E.W. "Bill,", 1949-1951 (Box-folder 14: 17)
  - E, 1934-1979 (Box-folder 14: 18)
    Correspondents include James Evan and Ecnomics Press, Inc.
  - Exter, John, 1973-1986 (Box-folder 14: 19)
  - Family, 1941-1979 (Box-folder 14: 20)
  - Field Enterprises Educational Corporation (World Book Encyclopedia) and the Ford Foundation, 1949-1959 (Box-folder 14: 21)
    Includes clippings and correspondence from Henry Ford II of the Ford Motor Company regarding the Ford Foundation.
  - Foundation for Economic Education (FEE), Inc., 1949-1987 (Box-folder 14: 22-23)
  - FEE and Business LAB (Learn About Business) program, 1957-1987 (Box-folder 15: 1)
    Included program materials and LAB questionnaires with feedback.
  - Friedman, Milton, 1978-1987 (Box-folder 15: 2)
  - G, 1942-1984 (Box-folder 15: 3)
  - General, 1942-1984 (Box-folder 15: 4)
  - Greaves, Bettina Bien and Percy I., 1955-1985 (Box-folder 15: 5)
  - Grocery Manufacturers of America, Inc., 1967 (Box-folder 15: 6)
    Includes report by Koether on food manufacturing and the Consumer Advisory Council.
  - H, 1963-1985 (Box-folder 15: 7)
    Correspondents include: Harazti, Zoltan (author of "John Adams and the Prophets of Progress," Harvard University Press 1964); Hill and Knowlton, Inc. (public relations firm); and Bank of Hawaii.
  - Hayek, Friedrich A., 1961-1981 (Box-folder 15: 8)
  - Hazlitt, Henry, 1962-1984 (Box-folder 15: 9)
  - Helms, Jesse, 1981 (Box-folder 15: 10)
  - The Hoover Institution on War, Revolution and Peace, 1975-1987 (Box-folder 15: 11)
  - Howard, John A. (Rockford College Institute), 1978-1979 (Box-folder 15: 12)
  - I, 1935-1978 (Box-folder 15: 13)
  - Ingersoll-Rand Corporation, 1976-1978 (Box-folder 15: 14)
  - Institute for Human Studies, Inc., 1972-1982 (Box-folder 15: 15)
  - Ivashenko, Marina Jolanta (1978 Ludwig von Mises Memorial Essay Contest), 1978-1989 (Box-folder 15: 16)
  - Jennings, John Q., and Johnson, Vassal G. (Financial Secretary of the Government of the Cayman Islands), 1974-1975 (Box-folder 15: 17)
  - John Birch Society, 1961-1979 (Box-folder 15: 18)
    Includes materials on the topics of communism and political Zionism.
  - K, 1970-1987 (Box-folder 15: 19)
    Keller, Anton; Kemp, Jack F.; Koch, Charles.
  - Lagenberg, Harry, 1977-1978 (Box-folder 15: 20)
  - Lambsdorff, Count Otto Graff (Bundesminister für Wirtschaft), 1977-1978 (Box-folder 15: 21)
  - Leoni, Bruno, 1960-1968 (Box-folder 15: 22)
  - The Liberal Party Organisation (United Kingdom), 1957 (Box-folder 15: 23)
  - Libertarian International, 1984-1986 (Box-folder 16: 1)
  - Liberty Fund, Inc., 1980-1986 (Box-folder 16: 2)
  - Malone, George W. (Senator, New Mexico), 1957-1958 (Box-folder 16: 3)
  - McOsker, Gerald, 1934-1940 (Box-folder 16: 4)
  - Mont Pelerin Society--Hamilius, Jean-Pierre, 1972 (Box-folder 16: 5)
  - Mott, Charles Stewart (C.S. Mott--General Motors Corp.), 1951-1953 (Box-folder 16: 6)
  - Murdoch, Katherine (Dynamic America, Inc.), 1953 (Box-folder 16: 7)
  - Myers, Edith, 1956-1958 (Box-folder 16: 8)
  - Navarro-Vásquez, Augustín, 1973-1979 (Box-folder 16: 9)
  - P, 1958-1983 (Box-folder 16: 10)
    Correpsondents include Paul Poirot (FEE), Political Economy Research Center, and T. Boone Pickens Jr.
  - Piano donation, 1978-1988 (Box-folder 16: 11)
  - Quirk, William J., 1982 (Box-folder 16: 12)
  - R, 1928-1983 (Box-folder 16: 13)
    Correspondents include Roger Randerson, Leonard Read (FEE), and Rockford College Institute.
  - The Reason Foundation, 1983 (Box-folder 16: 14)
  - Regnery, Henry; Regnery Gateway, Inc. (book publisher), 1963-1984 (Box-folder 16: 15)
  - Rockwell, Llewelyn H., 1983 (Box-folder 16: 16)
  - Röpke, Wilhelm, 1961-circa 1966 (Box-folder 16: 17)
  - Rothbard, Murray, 1960-1981 (Box-folder 16: 18)
  - S, 1958-1987 (Box-folder 16: 19)
    Correspondents include Captain Andrew Sherbu of USAF (West Point Military Academy), B.R. Shenoy (Economics Research Center), Wallace Stegner, and Robert Smith.
  - Sennholz, Dr. Hans F., 1953-1987 (Box-folder 16: 20)
  - Shenfield, Arthur, 1976-1978 (Box-folder 16: 21)
  - Shoeck, Helmut, 1957-1978 (Box-folder 16: 22)
  - Spiritual Mobilization, 1951-1952 (Box-folder 16: 23)